We want to be the bridge between all the financial assets around the world
U s d t on trong has way more value than the t r i
You know , on the tral network
In the future , we want to collaborate with black rock
to collaborate with new york stock exchange
Now stock to bring trailings of dollars onto the tral network
Is an hour of elon masks time really worth thirty million dollars to you for me
Definitely i i think so
I want to ask you about twenty twenty five
You , you did some really cool things
One of them i'm very jealous of i've always had a big fascination with space
You went into space in august last year on blue origin
It costs you twenty eight million dollars to do
Was it worth it
Yeah , totally
I think it's worth it
And , uh , we are just getting started , right
So i think , uh , bgon , uh
Journey is just the first step
You know , right now
I think us is working on is on like moon mission
And i also , uh , invested , um
Uh , space company focus on building space station
Uh , uh , in the future
So , um
so basically , i think in the future
We have all bunch of space hotels
So everyone can not only go into space
But they can also live in some place in the space
Right
And then , you know
Uh , further like people will go to moon more
You know , go to mars
You know , uh , step by step
So , so that's why i think space
Uh , especially on private , uh , space exploration
I think it's just started , right
So i , i , i think when i first win the blue in auction
I think in the twenty twenty one
Around those years there's only , uh , states astronaut
Private astronaut is like less than ten of them
But right now i is grow like , uh
I , i'm the seven hundred and twelve
Uh , astronaut in the space
Uh , and i , i think there is already like two hundred
You know , uprivate astrala , uh
And eventually i believe it's definitely gonna be more uprivate as stronthan , uh , states astronaut
So , so that's why i think this is just started
And you know , we will keep monitoring and keep
You know , thinking of
You know , how we can devil more in the future in the space
Look , um , you mentioned mars , uh
I think it was a couple of weeks ago
you said that you were willing to pay elon musk
Thirty million dollars to spend an hour talking to him
What would you want to chat to him
I'm . i'm sure it's probably about space
I'm i'm sure it's about ai
But yeah
I mean , no , is an hour of elon masks time
Really worth thirty million dollars to you
Uh , for me
Um
Uh , definitely i , i think so , right
I think some people
Uh , post the comments below
My twitter says like elon actually making forty million dollars an hour
You know , hh , for the company
So is he gonna lose like ten million dollars if he , uh
He , he spent like an hour talking to me
So that's why , you know , i , i think first of all is definitely worth it
And of course
I think , uh , ellow , of course
I think will teach me more then warren buffet
You know
Because , you know , warn buffet is more focused on , uh , the past
You know , uh , financial industry by elon is focused on the future , right
So he is working on really cool
Uh , company , uh , uh
And really cool , uh , new things
So that , that's why , uh
I always want to learn from him
And i , i , i think also
I will be a very good friend
And very , uh , uh , good asii will say to , uh , elon musk
Because you know , i think elon is focusing on making rockets , right
But elon himself won't be able to i
I think rich to the mars or to the moon
Uh , in the , in the future
He just focused on focusing on building , uh
Those utransportation , uh , infrastructure , right
So , but i am the person
You know , who is willing to go to mars
Going to the moon
You know , if , if i have chats
I , i already see some people , um
Star like a pull
Uh , pull on the
Uh , polly market about like
Whether justin sung gmelon mask in twenty thirty six
And no , we will see
We will see the results
H yeah
We'll have to see maybe , uh
Maybe someone will make a good bet
And , and , and they'll , they'll make some money
And playing with the raw like sixty percell something
You know , from the sounds of what you're saying it
It seems like it's , um
It's pretty likely , um
I wanna , i wanna bring , uh , the attention back to , to tron
And , you know , some big news coming out this week and integration with wallet connect
And , you know , uh , quin telegraphs , uh
Audience is , is very familiar with wallet connect
This integration is gonna bring six hundred wallets
Seventy thousand deaps to tr
Uh , you must be really pleased to get this one over the line
Yes
So we , uh , actually
You know , we are very lucky we get
Uh , moly connect support
And we got metasks support as well
Um
So in , um , these two weeks
Even though , you know , we signing those partnership like , uh , last year
but , uh , we , we are very pleased
We can get all those jobs done
Uh , in , in , in the first months in
Uh , twenty twenty six
You know , we have a lot more integration and partnership
You know , uh , could i running out like every week
Uh
But of course i think for the volley connect
Uh , is a great milestone
And i , i think happy to see , uh
All users and developers they can now , uh
Uh , devp on tron
Is it's way easier than , uh , before
I've
I've got a few more questions that
I think i'll just save until till the end of the , the interview that , uh
Will wrap things up quite nicely
But i want to move it on now to y specifically the ecosystem tron and tron , the blockchain
How people are using it
If you look at metrics like stable coin u s d t on tron
Hidden all time high of eighty three billion dollars
Why aren't more people talking about this
And um
How big is that metric
I , i , i think people really underrated
So basically , um , um
The u s d t on tron
Uh , it has more way more value than the t r i
You know , on the tral network
So i , i think that's also , you know
We can interpret this , uh , number in several ways
First of all , you know , tx is on the value a little bit
But also i think it's a good indication for basically
Tx is , uh , serving like all the stable quiet
All the developers and all the , uh
Uh , issues , uh , in the space in , in a very humble way , right
So , so basically , uh
I , i think we want every developpers on our ecosystem
Has more valuation than the infrastructure itself
I think heather like ut is just started . right
In the future
We want to , uh , collaborate with black rock
You know , to collaborate with new york stock exchange
Not stock to bring
You know , trailings of dollars until the tral network , right
So we want to be the network can host , you know
Tens of trainings dollars
Uh , in , in the future
So , so that's why i think right now is just like a ua beta past in your mind
What is trans killer use case
Because it seems pretty clear to me that it's one of the best chains for general stable coin payments and hemittances
Yeah
Uh , you've just said that you'd love to see , you know
Trillions of dollars from big players like black rock
And , you know , big , um
Institutional and players in the united states
Like the new york stock exchange
Thought operating on tron
Um
Yeah
What's your big idea here
Yes
Of course
For us
We want to build the
Uh , global settlement layer , right
For , uh
Every , uh , the developers like every issues in the world
Uh , recently i see the news new york stock exchange
Now stock exstock exchange is trying to build twenty four seven
Uh , settlement for the socks on the exchange
And i believe like stable coin will be a big part of it , right
So , because if you are one
Basically those stocks to get , uh , access by
Uh , people in china
Uh , people in india , like people in europe
You know , in africa
I think block changed the only way
So people like globally have this kind of the twenty four seven
Uh , settlement in the future that's the most like powerful way to do it
So , so that's why we want to be the bridge , uh
Between all the , uh , final financial assets around the world
So , so that's , you know , something
We try to do , uh
We tried to collaborate with every players in the space , uh
Because i think eventually it's gonna benefit everyone in the industry
Yeah
Look , you made mention of the sheer scale and , and the volume
And the value that you want to bring on to tron
You know , if it's trillions of dollars
Uh , at the end of the day
You're gonna have , or you're gonna need efficiency at scale
Which , which brings me to uan important part of this conversation today
Which is , um , the , uh
Tron settlement batching layer proposal
Which was put forward by boosty labs on coin telegraphs decentralization guardians dev hubb
Have you had a look at this
And what are your general thoughts on the batching proposal
And why this might be a major improvement for , for tras a whole if , uh
Very big players in the industry want to settle millions
If not tens of millions of dollars worth of value
Uh , on tron in the future
Yes
Totally
So first of all
I think we are a welcome like everybody to participate in trong , uh , governance , uh
And , uh , ecosystem building
So try is a permission this , uh , network
You know , from day one
So like everybody can run validators
You know , if they can get , uh , enough
You know , tx are voting in the ecosystem
Uh , they can become like like a blog producer
Uh , um , in in in the network
So , uh , since the beginning
You know , we have seen community developers
You know , we become the validators , uh
And we have seen like binance cracking tether
You know , ok ax
Okay coin japan
You know , all different
Uh , uh , industry players to be the validators on tral network
And also we have seen lots of like state providers
Um
I also become the validators on ta network
Uh , in the future
You know , for me
I think in the future
Probably one day
I think all the major states in the world
Uh , will run trm validors too
Because , you know , they want to be a part of the
Uh , uh , participation other tron
Their work as well
I , i think this is the way to go
Because for myself
You know , i always want to build , uh
Decentralized network and decentralized future
You know
Because i think this is the future of finance , right
So the reason why we invented by quiet , um
Uh , uh , uh , is , is basically we want to decentralize
Uh , the financial ecosystem
Rather than just , uh
Believing , you know , federal reserve
You know , believing , you know , city banks
You know , big banks in the world
They will settle your transaction
Uh , rather than , uh , believe the algorithm
Uh , believe the cold itself , right
Right now , um
The tron , uh , is only have java , uh
Java , uh , version right now . we , uh
We gonna ride , uh , c plus plus
And new , uh , all different
Uh , new , uh , languages
So i basically to get access to more developers around the world
If they want to run any of the triumph structure , uh , way easier
Because before that we need to
Uh , rewrite the , uh
The cold in a different language
But right now we
We all do it with ai
So , but of course we will do a fully audit , right
So ai , right it first
And we have a fully audit to make sure it's one hundred percent secure
But of course with the help of ai
Uh , right now we can
Uh , get trong notes and tron
Where is , uh , uh , access to all the developers in the world
Um , in all environment
Yep
Look i you've been around in the industry for a long time
And i'm sure you've watched with a great interest
The , the development and the evolution of some of the other big blockchain protocols out there
Ethereum leaned very heavily into layer two protocols
Uh , you know , as zk proofs have now become a big backbone of , of
How everything is happening on l tus , um
People are batching transactions
Uh , aps are doing that
And then they are submitting
You know , zkp back to the l one
Uh , for finality and , and settlement that's essentially what , um
This new proposal is doing , uh
Or , or proposing for the tron network
So , um
Where do you think beatch transactions would be most relevant on tron
And is it something you personally believe would be important to
To push , push forward , uh , as an ecosystem
Yeah
Totally
I think we always , you know , uh
Want to find the scale solution , right
So , uh , and , and , you know , uh , um , defra
I think esyan is definitely , uh , uh , doing the right thing
So i think , you know , for tron
You know , we have we more , uh , um , transaction
You know , uh , capability than ethereum
But , you know
A scale solution , um
And as you said , right , by backing transaction
Uh , batch transaction
We will always be good on top
Because we as always , you know , uh
We want to have safer , cheaper
Uh , faster transaction old time , right
Uh , um , uh
Because i , i believe eventually
Everyone in the world will join the block industry , right
So , uh , we always need to ask ourselves
Are we ready for that
Do we have the best infrastructure for that
But yeah , uh , i , i , i think definitely
I think we , uh , that's the right direction
Justin , can you , can you give us a sense of some of the most important , uh , tips
Trand improvement proposals that you've probably seen go through the governance process over the last few years
And also just a little bit about what that process looks like
Because like you mentioned before
It's important that the dao operates like it does
And , and the tron ecosystem is decentralized then , um
You know , tr x holders have , um
And a stake in the governance of the protocol
And decide what , you know , people can
And can't do in the future of the protocol
Um
Yeah
Just , just a , just an overview of tips is in the past that have made the most impact on tron
As a blockchain
And the governance , um
And process itself
Yes
I think for the most famous tip , uh
I , i think it's , uh
Uh , last year for the fear reduction
So actually , you know , before the fareduction
I think trong , uh , is making a lot of money
I think it's like three billion dollars or something
All for the network holders
So , uh , all the fee generated on tt blockchain
So one hundred percent goes to brand , uh
And some of , um
It's goes to , uh , subsidize
You know , the steakers on the network
So , um , and , and this
Uh , free reduction , um
Plants are actually reduced the , uh
Like billions of dollars of the revenue on network
But i think it's worth it
Because , uh , it's give more opportunity and cheaper transaction
Uh , for all the transactions on network
So , so people basically can do more
Right , uh , with , uh
With the money they hold
And i , i think will generate more transaction , uh , eventually
Yeah
I believe , you know , uh , uh
We need to be a little bit cautious
You know , uh , in the future
When we adopt and discuss , uh , tip
because it's gonna 啊 Impact on 啊 more people then
You know , when we first funded protocol , right
First fed protocol
We only have few million users use , uh
And , you know , uh
Because we have seen , you know , lots of protocols
They don't have much users
If they go down for like two hours
Nobody gonna even pay attention to it
But for tron network is no joke
Because like every seconds , um
This process , you know
Uh , are lots of transactions right now
The average , you know
Uu s dollars amount
You know , volume tron our process
It's around , uh , forty billion dollars , um
So being processed like every day
So the every second , you know , right now we are talking right
There is a tens of million dollars
You know , being transferred in the network
And we want to make sure , you know
Every transaction is safe
You know , get validated and get delivered on the network
So , so that's why i believe the safety
Yeah
It's always the number one priority
Look i'm , i'm very curious to , to hear your general thoughts on the future of tron now
And , um
Obviously quin telegraph is , is very hot , uh
very proud to have ct dg and ct dg dev hub as a place
Where developers across different blockchains can come and submit proposals
Um , engage
And we would love to see
You know , tip batch , uh
Go through and gets
You know , support of yourself and , and the wider tron ecosystem
Because i think there is a belief that it
It could help a lot with the scale
If indeed , you know , trillions of dollars start getting settled on tron
But as the founder of tron u
What kind of proposals are probably most relevant for the protocol today
Or in twenty twenty six
And where do you think , uh
You would like to see some improvements in
In the next year or five years
Yes
Scale is definitely , you know , one of the direction , right
We want to go
Uh , and also , uh
We always , you know , committed to make the transaction cheaper , uh
And network faster and handle more transactions , right
Um , um
Basically , i think , uh , uh , last year , uh
We have been , you know
Try to make the network cheaper , uh
Because how long it will take to finalize a , a , a a block , right
So i think before that we are doing three seconds to finalize the block
So right now we want to reduce this to one seconds or something , right
So we was you basically working on it
Uh , to make it faster
And , uh , uh , cheaper
Yeah
I think , i think everyone envisions a future way
We , we tap using whatever tron or , you know
If it's usd t on tron or any of the other chains
You tap it like you would tap with apple pay
And , and the , you know
The transaction just goes through and , and
And that is the future that we want to move towards
Um
Look , i , i , i've stolen a lot of your time today
So i'm gonna
I'm gonna wrap up with a couple of more questions
I think , uh , a big one is obviously
What's been going on in the united states
Um , the genius act made a load of really positive , uh , progress
And then obviously there's been , uh
You know , a little bit of a hiccup with the clarity act
Uh , coin base pulling , pulling their support in its current state
Um
But in general , it seems very positive that stable queens are quite literally becoming the future of finance
What to you is , is the biggest driver of our industry going into twenty twenty six
And , and maybe some
Some key trains that , that you think will play out this year
Yeah
I think for , uh , twenty twenty six
You know , uh , we're gonna keep like building
You know , and keep delivering , uh
Since , you know , already on the pipeline
And of course i think the
The regulation clarity is very important
Uh , for the industry players
So that's also my point of view , right
For the , uh , clarity at i
I think it's always , you know
Bad regulation is better than no regulation and no clarity , right
Because if we have like even a bad regulation
We can challenge it , right
We can change it
You know , uh , bu
Uh , core cases by debating
You know , uh , in , in , in the que room
Uh , rather than , you know , no clarity
So there's no , no way you can
You can change it
You know , there's no direction
You can go , right
So , so that's why i , i think right now
U s is finally start to move to the right direction
So , uh , i , i think more developers will come in
And more players traders will come in when they see the clarity , right
So , so that's also very important
And also of course , i think we devb it's like globally
It's also very important
Right
So , so that's why i , i , i'm also also committed to building the globlockchain
Like globally to get more users like everyone
Access u to the financial ecosystem are in the future
Justin , firstly , thank you so much for taking the time to chat to us
Um , it's really interesting to you to pick your brain on development etron
And , and of course quin telegraph is kei interested in helping the wider , um , blockchain ecosystem
Uh , thrive and stay decentralized through our quin telegraph decentralization guardians initiative
And then of course you've also got ct dg dev hub where developers , um , can go
And , you know , make proposals for different blockchains and engage in these proposals
So , um , thank you so much for your time
We look forward to catching up with you in twenty twenty six
I hope your fitness journey goes well
Um
I hope that you get to go into space again this year perhaps
And yeah
I also hope we
We get to find your meeting person as well
But thanks again for your time and have a fantastic year
Thank you
Thank you guys